<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>ype</title>
 <link href="http://ype.env.sh/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://ype.env.sh/"/>
 <updated>2014-08-15T12:35:39+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://ype.env.sh</id>
 <author>
   <name>anton</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Silver Searching in Emacs</title>
   <link href="http://ype.env.sh/blog/silver-searching-in-emacs"/>
   <updated>2014-04-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ype.env.sh/blog/silver-searching-in-emacs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; always seem to run into the constant
problem of having to change multiple variables, symbols, function
names, and other usually mundane parts of my code on a regular
basis. Most likely due to the fact that I first name everything in a
random, train of thought manner, only realising later that a more
useful, explanatory definition is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until last night I found myself opening and closing multiple files
after spending a few minutes in each finding and replacing keywords,
and then ultimately running my code to find out I missed a few in this
file, and a few in that file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take for example two files - one named foobar, and the other named
foofoo. In both foobar and foofoo I have a something with the keywords
foofunct. Now this something (variable, function, whatever) needs to
have the same name in both these files. So I decided while editing
the first file foobar that I want to change foofunct to foodef. With
the change made to foobar lock in place and saved, I attempt to run my
code, ultimately to be greeted by the wonderful world of errors saying
something of the sort &amp;ldquo;your doing it wrong, I can&amp;rsquo;t find your flipping
foofunct in foofoo anymore because it&amp;rsquo;s not in foobar&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this is an ongoing problem I&amp;rsquo;ve had and have always thought there
has to be a better way&amp;#x2026;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Well maybe I&amp;#39;m just ignorant&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &amp;ldquo;The Silver Searcher&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;ag&amp;rdquo; for sort. Ag is a wonderful
command line tool that lets you quickly search a code file, or set of
files, to find a specific keyword within those file. Ag from the
command line is awesome, but Ag in Emacs is amazing. By adding a few
simple lines to my dotemacs file I am not able to find, replace, and
view a single keyword across multiple files within a matter of
seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Adding some silver to your search (the code bit)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First you are going to have to make sure you have ag installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Mac you can do this through homebrew very easily (if you don&amp;rsquo;t have
homebrew installed already, join the future and install it)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Homebrew&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;$ brew install the_silver_searcher
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Macports&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;$ port install the_silver_searcher
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linux (Debian/Ubuntu)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;$ apt-get install silversearcher-ag
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;note: substitute &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; for whichever package manager you use regularly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;In your dotemacs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your dotemacs you need a few things. (before you do anything use
&lt;code&gt;M-x package-install&lt;/code&gt; to get the required packages &lt;code&gt;ag&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;wgrep&lt;/code&gt;
(optional (projectile)) ;;it makes things a whole lot nicer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lisp language-lisp&quot; data-lang=&quot;lisp&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;executable-find&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;ag&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;ag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;wgrep-ag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;setq-default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;ag-highlight-search&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;global-set-key&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;kbd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;H-q&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;ag-project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;global-set-key&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;kbd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;H-z&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;projectile-ag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;; if you have projectile&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you might noticed I am using Hyper-q &lt;code&gt;H-q&lt;/code&gt; and Hyper-z &lt;code&gt;H-z&lt;/code&gt; as
hot keys for ag-*(whatever), you can change these to suit your
preferred keybinding style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few other useful keybindings you may want to check out are &lt;code&gt;C-x
C-p&lt;/code&gt;, this makes the search buffer writable and lets you edit results
inline. Also, &lt;code&gt;C-c C-f&lt;/code&gt;, which activates
&lt;code&gt;next-error-follow-minor-mode&lt;/code&gt;, a nifty feature that quickly opens the
file matching the search result your cursor is currently over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gif show at the top of this page is a demo of how I use it to
navigate my emacs.d nightmare...here it is again so you don&amp;#39;t have to
scroll up to see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2014-04-08-silver-searching-in-emacs/silverSearcher.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Silver Searching in Emacs&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;blockquote style=&quot;border-left: 10px solid #D5D5D5;&quot;&gt;Silver Searching in Emacs&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;In (somewhat of a haphazard) Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the setup complete you can now move you cursor over any variable,
function name, definition, word, whatever and run ag on it to find all
the uses of it in either a project, file, or if you&amp;rsquo;re feel
ambitious your entire system (be warned, this sucks the life out of
everything and may take a billion years to complete)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Problematic Procrastination</title>
   <link href="http://ype.env.sh/blog/problematic-procrastination"/>
   <updated>2013-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ype.env.sh/blog/problematic-procrastination</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;It&lt;/span&gt; never ceases to amaze me how long I can procrastinate before
actually deciding to get shit done. It would maybe be not as troubling
if I hated what I do on a daily basis, or the work that I had to get
done was mind numbing dull, but it&amp;rsquo;s unfortunately not (I saw
unfortunately because then I would have an excuse as to why I&amp;rsquo;m a lazy
sod).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Brief notes on a day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to say I wake up energised and rearing to go, but like
most, I wake in a fog, dragging my sulking ass out of bed, trying
desperately to summon some celestial force to help me muster the focus
to stay on track with tasks I need to get done. Side note: Freelance
is the procrastinators worst nightmare (although I have found many a
way to procrastinate in a normal work environment as well, see also:
reverse toilet sleeping)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After raking large amounts of crust from my tired eyes I start my
already behind day with a cup of tea and a wonderfully delicious
cigarette (if you don&amp;rsquo;t smoke you should try it, really it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of
fun (no sarcasm, just pure smoking love))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smoking and tea drinking over, I either turn on some stupid cartoon on
one of a handful of streaming TV websites and proceed to say at the
end of every episode &amp;ldquo;after this one I&amp;rsquo;ll get to work&amp;rdquo; - this has
become problematic to the point that I downloaded an app to block
specific sites (unfortunately I never turn this app on).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once TV show watching has been completed I continue doing absolutely
useless, time wasting activities - one of my favourite being the
aimless pursuit of customising Emacs to the point of insanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Emacs Curse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe Richard Stallman whilst designing Emacs, deviously devised
to create a piece of shit, almost text editor, time vampire that was
more addictive then Facebook or all its other time sucking
compadres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half serial time killer, half insane genius, Stallman created the bane
of my existence, as for some reason I feel as though changing my
dotemacs file is somehow kind of like doing actual work - this is not
the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The calm after the storm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the drudge through the wasteland that is my morning over, actual
money making, cash flowing work can begin - this usually means
possibly taking a shower and then eating food so that around 3pm I can
start sewing, soldering, or hacking some slapped together, haphazardly
made project together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all work does get done and deadlines are hit, but oh how I
crave the day when this process is mitigated down to a streamline
flow making a 40 hour work week possibly possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;In (ardently needed) conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a love hate thing in my opinion - procrastination is beautiful -
almost wonderful to say the least - the unfortunate part is that
ignorance does not exist, making it virtually impossible to forget the
fact that if all the chaff could be removed, I might actually build
something useful for myself, and possibly others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another 20 minutes down the drain writing this god forsaken pile of
empty words - I really hope you didn&amp;rsquo;t read to the end of this - if so
go to some work, or find a better blog to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like turtles.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>virtually, a new beginning</title>
   <link href="http://ype.env.sh/blog/virtually-a-new-beginning"/>
   <updated>2013-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ype.env.sh/blog/virtually-a-new-beginning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I decided, one fateful day (or maybe not so fateful, but rather
ill-conceived) - that it would be a good idea to blog using orgmode. I
use orgmode for many things - scheduling, expenses, charts of varying
kind, time-tracking, the list goes on. Blogging in org seemed like a
natural extension of this already ill-fated, ill-conceived, awesomely
nerd trapped system I have developed for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How it all came together&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog uses a combination of a few tools that have become very dear
to me - the aforementioned orgmode, ispell (because I&amp;rsquo;m using friggin
emacs to write all this drivel), a ruby static site generator - nanoc,
and some hacked together bits of code (one of which is org-ruby, I&amp;rsquo;ll
explain this one in detail at a later time - there is a surprisingly
limited amount of documentation on how to use it effectively)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this heaping junk pile of snippets has come together in
isoty.pe - my effort to help clog the stinking drain that the Internet
has become (don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong I spend a good majority of my time in
this cesspool of delights).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;In [very needed] Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel I should warn, alert, tell you what you will encounter on this
site - don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid, it&amp;rsquo;s not a NSFW warning (it could be a little
though I guess, as your boss probably would not enjoy you wasting
endless hours looking at pointless pictures of pandas) - the site is
my endless hacking, tweaking, replace-stringing of the various tools I
use on a daily basis to GSD (for the GTD crowd GSD is my version where
I replace the David Allen acronym &amp;ldquo;Get Things Down&amp;rdquo; with the more
work appropriate &amp;ldquo;Get Shit Done&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy this journey to the deep, bon voyage to sanity, this
different, but hopefully better foray into Internet cesspiting.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
